Phil Rajchgot

Full-Stack Web Developer

514.808.8070 | tophil@outlook.com | linkedin.com/in/philraj | github.com/philraj

SUMMARY

I'm a full-stack JavaScript web developer who's passionate about learning new technologies and writing clean, expressive code. I enjoy taking on challenges to better myself and hone my craft. I have team experience, working with front end frameworks like React and jQuery, as well as back end technologies such as Node.js, Express, and MySQL.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End JavaScript (ES2015), React, jQuery, CSS3, HTML5

Back End ▶ Node.js, Express, Socket.io, MySQL, Sequelize, bcrypt

Tools ▶ Git, GitHub, Webpack, Babel, Promises

PROJECTS

JSBOT

https://github.com/philraj/JSbot

JSbot is a web-controllable Raspberry Pi robot. The React-based interface exposes multiple control schemes and a live, low-latency video feed pulled from the robot's camera. Commands and video data are passed between the client and the server (running on the Raspberry Pi) through web sockets.

- · Front end built with React, socket.io, and jsmpeg
- · Back end built with Node.js, Express, socket.io, johnny-five and raspi-io

PROMISES FROM SCRATCH

https://github.com/philraj/promises-from-scratch

This is an A+ spec-conformant promise library, that features basic functionality found in other promise implementations. I created this project to gain a deeper understanding of how promises work in JavaScript.

- · Written using ES2015 JavaScript
- · Includes a demonstration of the library when run from the command line

EDUCATION

DECODEMTL FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP — Montreal, QC January – March 2016

Completed an intensive two-month course in full-stack JavaScript web development. Technologies learned:

- · Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, socket.io, Promises (Back-End)
- HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, React, socket.io (Front-End)
- · Webpack, Babel, NPM, CLI, Git & Github (Build Process / Team Communication)

CONCORDIA UNIVERSITY, Computer Science — Montreal, QC 2007 – 2009

Learned the fundamentals of computer science, taking courses in the following subjects:

- · Object-oriented programming
- · Data Structures & Algorithms
- · Advanced Program Design With C++
- · Introduction to Theoretical Computer Science
- Operating Systems
- · System Hardware
- Combinatorics

WORK HISTORY

IT & LAB TECHNICIAN – Dental clinic of Dr. Lucie Billette 2011 – 2015

- · Installed office equipment and set up the network
- · Performed regular software installations and updates
- · Used troubleshooting skills to promptly fix technical issues
- · Kept the laboratory and its equipment clean and organized

IT & WEB DESIGN – Sheldon Golberg Insurance Services Inc. 2009 – 2011

- · Installed and maintained computer systems and office equipment
- · Performed methodical troubleshooting to solve technical problems
- · Rebuilt the company's website (HTML, CSS)
- · Kept paperwork and documents organized
- · Collaborated on business projects